[Music]
Welcome to the Business Central launch
edition for 2025 release wave 2. This
session is about new demo data that you
can use for analytics or reporting.
So we have enhanced the demo data tool,
the Contoso demo data tool with a lot of
more types of data for different
document types simply because um we
wanted to make it we want to make it
easier to demo reporting and analytics.
So that means there are types of demo
data that is needed for reports and
PowerBI reports to show data. But we
also wanted to make sure that when you
showcase a PowerBI report or a built-in
report that it also showcases some
meaningful data. That means the demo
data we want for analytics is something
where we need variation. Maybe variation
in time, maybe variation in categories,
maybe variations in salespeople and so
on.
So what we have done in this release
wave is adding new or new demo data for
sales and for purchasing. So quotes,
blankets, sales orders, posted sales
orders and return orders for sales. And
for purchasing uh it's purchase orders
and posted purchase orders. So those are
available from the Kontoso demo tool.
Either you can install it from the tool
itself. It's called the name of that
package is called analytics or if you
spin up a new company with demo data
from Conso and just choose all the demo
data, you kind of get it uh there for
free.
Um so for sales quotes, before or
without this package, you you had two
sales quotes. Now you have 18 for
blanket sales orders. You had none. Now
you have four posted sales or invoices.
You have like 80 invoices posted more
than what you used to have. Um for
return orders you actually now have demo
data. Um in the past you would not have
that purchase orders are double up from
14 to 29. Um and we will continue that
investments in the next release wave
both like more types of demo data and
more types of entities but also trying
to um make more variation of the things
we have and we typically learn that we
when we see a PowerBI report with a
great story if only
there would be a distribution where
location would not be blank but
something right so whenever we learn
something we will enhance either with
new entries or with uh changing the
attributes for different documents. If
you want to learn more about the Kontoso
coffee demo project as as a whole, um I
wouldn't expect you to read that link or
click that. You can't do that in the
video, but we will add the link to the
description here on YouTube so you can
go and read about it uh the the project.
Maybe you want to contribute. This is an
open- source uh project. So uh so if if
you want to contribute with other things
uh maybe there's an opportunity for that
so that whatever you extend the demo
tool with uh for demo data for analytics
uh can be of help for others. There's a
one small difference between the demo
data for analytics and the like the
normal transactional demo data is that
we can be a little bit more free in what
we put in analytics. Um whereas the the
the other parts of Kontoso kind of need
to fit into the coffee story. Um so it
can be harder to extend the the other
module where the analytics were a little
bit more free. Also um you don't have to
install analytics and therefore it
doesn't necessarily have to completely
tie into the to the kind of the core
demo data. And this analytics is of
course not part of the core setup. So if
you install a new company and want the
chart of accounts, uh you will of course
not get these posted uh document or
these doc document demo data unless you
actually choose to enable it. So that's
it for demo data. Just a few more
things. Um if you're watching this
video, you're very likely a Business
Central partner, Microsoft partner. Um,
LinkedIn, if you're not following us on
LinkedIn, make sure you do aka.ms/bc
LinkedIn where you get like news of what
coming uh directly in that channel or
from that account. And similarly, uh,
make sure you watch the product group's
YouTube channel, aka.ms/bc
YouTube. Not only do we have what's new,
but also co-pilot and AI, tips and
tricks, deep dives, technical point of
view, and under the hood. Under the hood
is a new initiative we started last year
where we put in small snippets of things
that are coming in the upcoming release,
sometimes way before they hit the
release plan. And as a partner, you need
to know at least three resources. The
first is aka.ms/bcall.
That's the landing page for all AKA
links. And maybe browse through that to
see if there are resources you didn't
know. Second one is a Yammer. If you're
not on the Yammer channel, you're
missing out and your competitors will be
ahead of you because they have
conversations, questions about things in
Business Central. No customers are on
that network and if you're not there and
they are, well, they have a competitive
advantage. So, make sure that you join
Yammer. And the third is office hours,
aka.ms/off
hour, BC office hours. office hours are
happening once a month um typically and
they are covering things that are kind
of relevant for the future. So new
initiatives, things where you can come
and learn, ask questions. Uh make sure
that you go and at least know what's the
program for the next 6 monthsish.
that's on that AKA link and then join
the office hours from time to time to
kind of learn uh what what's coming in
uh in the area of Business Central. And
with that, that's it. Thank you so much
for watching and go and try out the new
demo data, give us feedback or do open
source contributions. Thank you.